<resources>


    <!-- TODO: Remove or change this placeholder text -->
    <string name="title_chapter1">
        Chapter 1: Understanding Depression
    </string>
    <string name="chapter1_content1">
        \n<b>Sadness</b> is something we all experience. It is a normal reaction to
        difficult times in life and usually passes with a little time.
        \n\nWhen a person has depression, it interferes with daily life and normal
        functioning.
        \n\nIt can cause pain for both the person with depression and
        those who care about him or her. Doctors call this condition
        “depressive disorder,” or “clinical depression.” It is a real illness.
        \n\nIt is not a sign of a person’s weakness or a character flaw. You can’t “snap
        out of” clinical depression.
        \n\nMost people who experience depression
        need treatment to get better.
    </string>
    <string name="chapter1_content2">
        \n<b>Signs and Symptoms</b>
        \n\nSadness is only a small part of depression.
        \n\nSome people with
        depression may not feel sadness at all.
        \n\nDepression has many other
        symptoms, including physical ones.
        \n\nIf you have been experiencing any of
        the following signs and symptoms for at least 2 weeks, you may be
        suffering from depression:

        \n\n• Persistent sad, anxious, or “empty” mood
        \n• Feelings of hopelessness, pessimism
        \n• Feelings of guilt, worthlessness, helplessness
        \n• Loss of interest or pleasure in hobbies and activities
        \n• Decreased energy, fatigue, being “slowed down”
        \n• Difficulty concentrating, remembering, making decisions
        \n• Difficulty sleeping, early-morning awakening, or oversleeping
        \n• Appetite and/or weight changes
        \n• Thoughts of death or suicide, suicide attempts
        \n• Restlessness, irritability
        \n• Persistent physical symptoms
    </string>
    <string name="chapter1_content3">
        \n<b>Major</b> depression: Severe symptoms that interfere with the ability
        to work, sleep, study, eat, and enjoy life. An episode can occur only
        once in a person’s lifetime, but more often, a person has several episodes.

        \n\n<b>Persistent depressive disorder:</b> A depressed mood that lasts for at
        least 2 years. A person diagnosed with persistent depressive disorder
        may have episodes of major depression along with periods of less
        severe symptoms, but symptoms must last for 2 years.
        Some forms of depression are slightly different, or they may develop
        under unique circumstances. They include:

        \n\n<b>Psychotic depression</b>, which occurs when a person has severe
        depression plus some form of psychosis, such as having disturbing false
        beliefs or a break with reality (delusions), or hearing or seeing
        upsetting things that others cannot hear or see (hallucinations).

        \n\n<b>Postpartum depression</b>, which is much more serious than the
        “baby blues” that many women experience after giving birth, when
        hormonal and physical changes and the new responsibility of caring for
        a newborn can be overwhelming. It is estimated that 10 to 15 percent
        of women experience postpartum depression after giving birth.

        \n\n<b>Seasonal affective disorder (SAD)</b>, which is characterized by the
        onset of depression during the winter months, when there is less
        natural sunlight. The depression generally lifts during spring and
        summer. SAD may be effectively treated with light therapy, but nearly
        half of those with SAD do not get better with light therapy alone.
        Antidepressant medication and psychotherapy can reduce SAD
        symptoms, either alone or in combination with light therapy.

        \n\n<b>Bipolar disorder</b> is different from depression. The reason it is included
        in this list is because someone with bipolar disorder experiences
        episodes of extreme low moods (depression). But a person with
        bipolar disorder also experiences extreme high moods (called “mania”).
    </string>

    <string name="title_chapter2">
        Chapter 2: Depression affects people in different ways
    </string>
    <string name="chapter2_content1"><b>Women</b>
        \n\nWomen with depression do not all experience the same symptoms.
        However, women with depression typically have symptoms of sadness,
        worthlessness, and guilt.
        \n\nDepression is more common among women than
        among men. Biological, lifecycle, hormonal, and
        psychosocial factors that are unique to women
        may be linked to their higher depression rate.
        For example, women are especially vulnerable to
        developing postpartum depression after giving
        birth, when hormonal and physical changes and
        the new responsibility of caring for a newborn
        can be overwhelming.
    </string>
    <string name="chapter2_content2"><b>Men</b>
        \n\nMen often experience depression differently than
        women. While women with depression are more
        likely to have feelings of sadness, worthlessness, and
        excessive guilt, men are more likely to be very tired,
        irritable, lose interest in once-pleasurable activities,
        and have difficulty sleeping.

        \n\nMen may turn to alcohol or drugs when they are
        depressed. They also may become frustrated,
        discouraged, irritable, angry, and sometimes
        abusive. Some men may throw themselves into
        their work to avoid talking about their depression
        with family or friends, or behave recklessly. And
        although more women attempt suicide, many more
        men die by suicide in the United States.
    </string>
    <string name="chapter2_content3">
        <b>Children</b>
        Before puberty, girls and boys are equally likely to
        develop depression. A child with depression may
        pretend to be sick, refuse to go to school, cling to
        a parent, or worry that a parent may die. Because
        normal behaviors vary from one childhood stage
        to another, it can be difficult to tell whether a child is just going through
        a temporary “phase” or is suffering from depression.
        \n\nSometimes the
        parents become worried about how the child’s behavior has changed,
        or a teacher mentions that “your child doesn’t seem to be himself.” In
        such a case, if a visit to the child’s pediatrician rules out physical symptoms,
        the doctor will probably suggest that the child be evaluated, preferably
        by a mental health professional who specializes in the treatment of
        children. Most chronic mood disorders,
    </string>
    <string name="chapter2_content4"><b>Teens</b>
        \n\nThe teen years can be tough. Teens are forming an identity apart from
        their parents, grappling with gender issues and emerging sexuality, and
        making independent decisions for the first time in their lives. Occasional
        bad moods are to be expected, but depression is different.
    </string>
    <string name="chapter2_content5"><b>Older People</b>
        \n\nHaving depression for a long period of time is not a normal part of
        growing older. Most older adults feel satisfied with their lives, despite
        having more illnesses or physical problems. But depression in older
        adults may be difficult to recognize because they may show different,
        less obvious symptoms.
        \n\nSometimes older people who are depressed appear to feel tired, have
        trouble sleeping, or seem grumpy and irritable. Confusion or attention
        problems caused by depression can sometimes look like Alzheimer’s
        disease or other brain disorders. Older adults also may have more
        medical conditions such as heart disease, stroke, or cancer, which may
        cause depressive symptoms. Or they may be taking medications with
        side effects that contribute to depression.
    </string>

    <string name="title_chapter3">
        Chapter 3: Depression is treatable
    </string>
    <string name="chapter3_content1"><b>Tests and Diagnosis</b>
        \n\nYour doctor or health care provider will examine you and talk to you at the appointment. Your doctor may do a physical exam and ask questions
        about your health and symptoms. There are no lab tests that can specifically diagnose depression, but your doctor may also order some lab tests to rule out other conditions.
    </string>


</resources>
